// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
//eASY JS
let questions = [


{
    numb:1,
    question:"Javascript is an_____ language?",
    answer:"A. Object-Oriented",
    options:[
    "A. Object-Oriented",
    "B. Object-Based",
    "C. Procedural",
    "D. None of the above",
    ]
},

{
    numb:2,
    question:"How can a datatype be declared to be a constant type?",
    answer:"A. const",
    options:[
    "A. const",
    "B. var",
    "C. let",
    "D. constant",
    ]
},

{
    numb:3,
    question:"Which of the following is not a variable declaration type?",
    answer:"D. int",
    options:[
    "A. var",
    "B. let",
    "C. const",
    "D. int",
    ]
},

{
    numb:4,
    question:"What symbol is used to denote single-line comments in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. //",
    options:[
    "A. //",
    "B. --",
    "C. ##",
    "D. **",
    ]
},

{
    numb:5,
    question:"What does DOM stands for in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. Document Object Model",
    options:[
    "A. Document Object Model",
    "B. Data Output Method",
    "C. Document Order Mechanism",
    "D. Dynamic Object Manipulation",
    ]
},

{
    numb:6,
    question:"Which of the following is NOT a primitive data type in Javascript?",
    answer:"D. Object",
    options:[
    "A. Boolen",
    "B. String",
    "c. Float",
    "D. Object",
    ]
},

{
    numb:7,
    question:"What does the 'typeof' operator return when used with a number varaiable?",
    answer:"B. 'number' ",
    options:[
    "A. 'string' ",
    "B. 'number' ",
    "C. 'boolean' ",
    "D. 'object' ",
    ]
},

{
    numb:8,
    question:"Which built-in method can be used to convert a string to uppercase letters in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. toUpperCase()",
    options:[
    "A. toUpperCase()",
    "B. uppercase()",
    "C. convertToupper()",
    "D. toUpper(),"
    ]
},

{
    numb:9,
    question:"What symbol is used for concatenating strings in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. +",
    options:[
    "A. +",
    "B. @",
    "C. $",
    "D. #",
    ]
},

{
    numb:10,
    question:"Which function is used to display a message in console panel Javascript?",
    answer:"A. console.log()",
    options:[
    "A. console.log()",
    "B. alert()",
    "C. prompt()",
    "D. confirm()",
    ]
},

{
    numb:11,
    question:"What will the following code output: console.log(2+ '2')",
    answer:"C. '22' ",
    options:[
    "A. 22",
    "B. 4",
    "C. '22' ",
    "D. Error",
    ]
},

{
    numb:12,
    question:"Which keyword is used to define a function in Javascript?",
    answer:"C. function",
    options:[
    "A. func",
    "B. method",
    "C. function",
    "D. def",
    ]
},

{
    numb:13,
    question:"Which method is used to remove the last element from an array in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. pop()",
    options:[
    "A. pop()",
    "B. shift()",
    "C. slice()",
    "D. removeLast()",
    ]
},

{
    numb:14,
    question:"What does the Javascript function isNaN() do?",
    answer:"B. Checks if a value is null",
    options:[
    "A. Checks if a value is an array",
    "B. Checks if a value is null",
    "C. Checks if avalue is not a number",
    "D. Checks if a value is a number",
    ]
},

{
    numb:15,
    question:"Which of the following is NOT a Javascript loop?",
    answer:"C. loop",
    options:[
    "A. for",
    "B. while",
    "C. loop",
    "D. do...while",
    ]
},

{
    numb:16,
    question:"What will the following code output: console.log(typeof(undefined))",
    answer:"A. 'undefined' ",
    options:[
    "A. 'undefined' ",
    "B. undefined",
    "C. 'null' ",
    "D. null",
    ]
},

{
    numb:17,
    question:"Which method is used t add elements to the end of an array in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. push()",
    options:[
    "A. push()",
    "B. unshift()",
    "C. add()",
    "D. append()",
    ]
},

{
    numb:18,
    question:"What is the javascript operator used to check if two values are equal in value and type?",
    answer:"B. ===",
    options:[
    "A. ==",
    "B. ===",
    "C. =",
    "D. !==",
    ]
},

{
    numb:19,
    question:"Which method is used to execute a function after a certain time interval in Javascript?",
    answer:"A. setTimeout()",
    options:[
    "A. setTimeout()",
    "B. setInterval()",
    "C. wait()",
    "D. delay()",
    ]
},

{
    numb:20,
    question:"What will the following code output:  console.log(0.3==='0.3')",
    answer:"B. False",
    options:[
    "A. True",
    "B. False",
    ]
}
    









  
  
];